OREST SZOPIAK

WEB DEVELOPER

orest.szopiak@gmail.com
647-267-3233
orest.cloud
linkedin.com/in/orest-szopiak
github.com/orest-cloud
Toronto, Ontario

My love of new challenges and creating rich web experiences has led me to transition from Digital Design to Web Development.

With a history of producing finely tuned interfaces, my experience manipulating graphics and layout has proven to be a great advantage in modular web design.

The keystones of my practice are reliability, attention to detail, and continuous learning.

SKILLS

Coding

Front-End: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS, SASS

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, Redux, Web APIs, User Authentication, OAuth

Testing: Jest

Development: GitHub, TypeScript

Graphics

XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, InVision, Figma

EXPERIENCE

Web Designer | Wolverine Worldwide

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

- Designing retail website landing pages and content using XD
- Coordinating with developers to launch brand style refreshes
- Working with multiple brand styles (Keds, Sperry, Saucony, Merrell)
- Optimizing/exporting media assets to specs (images, videos, animations)
- OA of content scheduled for launch

Graphic Designer | Inter-Web Services

MAY 2016 - MAR 2020, TORONTO, ON

- Designed and administered complex e-commerce websites
- Boosted site traffic by authoring engaging e-blasts and landing pages
- Interpreted analytics data in order to tailor experiences
- Standardized brand styles across digital platforms

Media Assistant | ELL Technologies

NOV 2015 - APR 2016, TORONTO, ON

- Implemented structure and content for language learning modules
- Sourced and managed hundreds of media files within a CMS
- Managed the media team's time and workload distribution

Graphic Designer | Sole Proprietorship

JUNE 2012 - OCTOBER 2015, TORONTO, ON

- Designed branding for small businesses: logos, fliers, business cards
- Designed 3-4 page WordPress websites

Flash Designer | Webkinz (Ganz Studios)

MAY 2008 - MAY 2012, TORONTO, ON

- Orchestrated user interfaces for interactive web entertainment
- Executed visuals and functionality based on spec documents
- Animated content through ActionScript
- Collaborated cross-functionally within an Agile Scrum framework

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development

NOV 2020 - FEB 2021, TORONTO, ON

Ryerson University | Bachelors in New Media, Image Arts

SEPT 2003 - JUNE 2007, TORONTO, ON

Final project appeared in Ryerson's Nuit Blanche showcase 2007

PROJECTS

Stomping Ground | Lead Coder

JAN 2021, BRAINSTATION

A React.js app that brings together data from three APIs: property listings, neighborhood walkability scores, and Google Maps Places photos.

https://orest.cloud/projects/stomping-ground